Guide to the Colonial Africa: Postcard Collection, 1880-1980
Department of Special Collections
Colonial Africa: postcard collection,
1880-1980
M0814
1.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Usually French photographers of French Africa. Three different accessions purchased from same dealer, although previous provenance is mixed. Some cards are written on; some not. Accession 1995-244 is in box 1, and consists of one album and 26 folders totaling some 500 cards. The photographers listed as added entries can all be found in this accession. Accession 2000-238 is in box 2 (Senegal, some 197 loose cards in folders) and in box 3 (album of ca. 300 cards of French West Africa, French Equatorial Africa, North Africa, Madagasca, Aden, Somali Coast, Union of South Africa, Zanaibar, etc.). Accession 2000-276 is also in box 3 and consists of an album of ca. 300 cards that are largely sub-Saharan Africa, mostly from former French colonies and the Belgian Congo, but also some from North Africa, Union of South Africa, and a scattering of other British-controlled territories. Approximately 90% of these were issued before 1940.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions on access.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 1995 and 2000.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Usually French photographers of French Africa. Three different accessions purchased from same dealer, although previous provenance is mixed. Some cards are written on; some not. Accession 1995-244 is in box 1, and consists of one album and 26 folders totaling some 500 cards. The photographers listed as added entries can all be found in this accession. Accession 2000-238 is in box 2 (Senegal, some 197 loose cards in folders) and in box 3 (album of ca. 300 cards of French West Africa, French Equatorial Africa, North Africa, Madagasca, Aden, Somali Coast, Union of South Africa, Zanaibar, etc.). Accession 2000-276 is also in box 3 and consists of an album of ca. 300 cards that are largely sub-Saharan Africa, mostly from former French colonies and the Belgian Congo, but also some from North Africa, Union of South Africa, and a scattering of other British-controlled territories. Approximately 90% of these were issued before 1940.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Acelaise, A.A., photographer.; Benyoumoff, J., photographer.; Bertou, photographer.; Bouhsira, J., photographer.; Fortier, A.O.F., photographer.; Geiser, J., photographer.; Kricorian, photographer.; Maillet, photographer.; Martin, L., photographer.; Venieris, M., photographer.; A. Albaret, Dakar.; A. Pleux et Truchi, edit., Fez.; Agenda P.L.M.; Anciens Etab. Neurdein et Cie., Paris.; C. Nataf.; C.A.P. (Compagnie des Arts Photomechaniques, Strasbourg); Cairo Postcard Trust, Cairo.; Cl. Andre.; Collection Generale Fortier, Dakar.; Collection Ideale, P.S., Algiers.; Collection N.D. Phot.; Collection Nouvelle, Mme Bouchut, editeur.; Comptoir Philatelique d'Egypte, Alexandria.; E.P.A. (Editions Photo-Africaines), Alger.; Edit. Horizons de France.; Edit. Joseph Helou, Dakar.; Edition Hell, Tangiers.; Edition J. Bousira, Fez.; Edition A. Sipecky, Oran.; EMT.; Ephtimios Freres, Port Said.; Geiser, J., photographer.; Helio Braun, Paris.; Isaac Behar, Port Said.; J. Barreau et Cie.; J. Benyoumoff et Ch. Djian.; J. Geiser, Algiers.; L. & H., Cairo.; Lehnert & Landrock, Cairo.; Leroux Alger, photographers.; Levy & Neurdein Reunis, Paris.; Lichtenstern & Harari, Cairo.; L'Oeuvre de la Propagation de la Foi, Paris.; Messageries Maritimes.; Nahon & Lasry, Tangiers.; ND Phot.; Nels, Brussels.; Neurdein et Cie., Paris.; Photo Vollenweider, Alger.; Societe des Missions Evangeliques, Paris.; Aden.; Africa, East.; Algeria.; Arabian peninsula.; Asia, Southeastern.; Basutoland.; Belgian Congo.; Casablanca (Morocco); Cote d'Ivoire.; Congo (Brazzaville); Congo (Democratic Republic); Dahomey.; Dakar (Senegal); Djibouti.; Ethiopia.; Egypt.; French Equatorial Africa.; French North Africa.; French West Africa.; Gabon.; German East Africa.; Ghana.; Guinea.; Khartoum (Sudan); Lesotho.; Libya.; Madagascar.; Malagasy Republic.; Mali.; Morocco.; Nigeria.; Oceania.; Oran (Algeria); Port Said (Egypt); Port Sudan (Sudan); Senegal.; Sierra Leone.; Somali Coast.; South Africa.; Sudan.; Suez Canal.; Togo.; Tunisia.; Turkey.; Union of South Africa.; Zanzibar.; Photoprints.; Postcards.
Collection Contents
- Series 1: Algeria
  - Subseries 1: Algiers
    - Subsubseries 1. Street Scenes
      - Street scenes in Casbah, no. 1n.d. (ca. 1900-1945), 12 postcards (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Contains images of women, children, and men in the Algiers Casbah in the first part of the 20th century, taken on the following streets: rue de la Mer Rouge; rue N'Fissa; rue Ben Ali; rue Sidi Abdaleh; Impasse Kleber. Includes one image of women weaving, several of men conversing in the streets, and several of veiled women.
        Photo Vollenweider, Alger; Children; Muslim women; Street scenes
      - Street scenes in Algiers, no. 2n.d. (ca. 1900-1919), 20 postcards (Box 1, Folder 2)
        Contains images of Algiers, including scenes from the Casbah, women, men and children, and street scenes of the following streets: rue Marengo; rue de la Mer Rouge; Rue d'Isly; Rue Bab Azoun; rue de la Liberte; rue Michelet; les Cinq Avenues and rue de Constantine; Boulevard Amiral-Pierre; rue Sadi-Carnot. Contains images of the following buildings; Au Bon Marche; Hotel Excelsoir; Hotel de la Regence; le Marche de la Lyre,
        Bougault, A. - photographer; Geiser, J. - photographer; C.A.P. (Compagnie des Arts Photomechaniques, Strasbourg); Collection Ideale, P.S.; Collection N.D. Phot; Collection Z. F., Alger; Edit. A.F.; Edition E.S.; Edit. Horizons de France; Editions L. & Y., Alger; P.H. & Cie., Nancy; Casbah; Children; Muslim Women; Panoramic views; Street Scenes
      - Buildings and landmarksn.d. (1900-1919), 20 postcards (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Contains postcards with images of various buildings and street scenes in Algiers and Mustapha. Images include: la place de la Republique; le Theatre municipal, Square Bresson; la Prefecture; le Musee; rue Dumont-d'Urville; le nouvel Hotel des Postes; le Lycee (Bugeaud); Avenue Bab-el-Oued. From Mustapha, images of the Arsenal d'Artillerie; Alexandra Hotel; Hotel Kirsch; Quartier Julienne.
        A. Parodi editions, Mustapha; Cartes "La Cigogne", Alger; Collection Ideale P.S.; Collection N.D. Phot; Editions E.S.; Editions Photo Africaines, Algiers; L.V. & Cie.; Levy et Fils, Paris (Edit. LL); Algeria, Description and travel; Architecture, colonial; Colonial cities; Street scenes
    - Subsubseries 2. Port
      - Port and Quaisn.d. (1900-1945), 11 postcards (Box 1, Folder 4)
        Contains images from the Port of Algiers. One postcard depicts an historical engraving of port and pier. Other images include: le Palais consulaire; les rampes; the railroad station; l'escalier de la pecherie; le Boulevard de la Republique; le Boulevard Carnot. Identified commercial buildings include: Imprimerie Jourdan; Hangars et Abris de la Chambre de Commerce; Ch. Schiaffino; A. Jouvet & Cie; L. Bergeret Fils; Vins A. Bonneville; A. Morris Minieri.
        CAP Collection Ideale P.S.; Edition E.S.; L.L.L.V. & Co.; Algeria, Description and travel; Architecture, colonial; Colonial cities; Railroad stations; Harbors; Commercial buildings
    - Subsubseries 3. Religious Buildings
      - Mosques, Algiersn.d. (1900-1925), 17 postcards (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Contains images of various mosques and other islamic religious buildings in Algiers. Includes images of Mosque Djamaa Djedid, la Grande Mosquee (El Kebir Mosque); the Medersa; Tombeau de la Reine; Mosquee de Sidi Abderhaman. Also images of la Place du Gouvernement; Statue du Duc d'Orleans; rue de la Marine.
        CAP; Collection Ideale P.S.; Edition E.S.; Editions A. Sipecky, Oran; J. Geiser, Alger L.L.L.V. & Co.; ND Phot; Algeria, Description and travel; Architecture, colonial; Colonial cities; Islam; Mosques; Religious buildings; Religious education; Street scenes
      - Governor's palaces and Christian religious buildingsn.d. (1900-1945), 13 postcards (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Contains postcards of the Palais d'ete du Gouverneur (Mustapha); Palais d'ete du Gouverneur (Algiers). Also contains images of Christian religious buildings in Algiers: the Cathedral and Notre-Dame d'Afrique.
        A.L. edit., Alger; Collection Ideale P.S.; CAP; Edit. A.F.; Edition E.S.; Edition L. & Y., Alger L.L.ND Phot; Algeria, Description and travel; Architecture, colonial; Basilicas; Cathedrals; Colonial cities; Religious buildings
  - Subseries 2: Cities
    - Subsubseries 4. A-C
      - Arzew, Bone, Bou-Saada, Cherchelln.d. (1900-1919), 5 postcards (Box 1, Folder 7)
        Contains postcards of the following towns: Arzew, Bone, Bou-Saada, Cherchell. Includes images of a covered market (Arzew); the port (Arzew); of street scenes (Bone; Cherchell); and the departure for the races (Bou-Saada).
        ND Phot; J. Geiser, phot., Alger; Leroux, Alger; Algeria, Description and travel; Horse racing; Markets; Panoramic views; Street scenes
    - Subsubseries 5. Biskra
      - Biskran.d. (1900-1945), 12 postcards (Box 1, Folder 8)
        Contains postcards from Biskra. Includes images of the Mosquee de Sidi-Mouna; le Fumoir du Chateau Landon; Hotel du Sahara. Images of la Rue Berthe, le Cercle Militaire; Rue des Ouled-Nails; la Grande Allee; la place du Marche. Also 2 postcards with images of caravans, 1 postcard of the Sahara desert.
        CAP; Collection Ideale, PS; J. Geiser, Alger; LL Maur, Biskra; ND Phot Arnold Vollenweider, Alger; Algeria, Description and travel; Architecture, colonial; Caravans; Casbah; Colonial cities; Deserts; Mosques; Street scenes
    - Subsubseries 6. Blida
      - Blidan.d. (1900-1970), 4 postcards (Box 1, Folder 9)
        Contains postcards from Blida. Includes images of the Place du Marche, the Place d'Alger, the Kiosque of the Place Georges Clemenceau, Gorges de la Chiffa.
        CAP; Algeria, Description and travel; Colonial architecture; Gorges; Markets; Street scenes
    - Subsubseries 7. Constantine, Philippeville
      - Constantine, Philippevillen.d. (1900-1930), 8 postcards (Box 1, Folder 10)
        Contains postcards from the towns of Constantine and Philippeville. The six postcards of Constantine contain images of the Gorges du Rummel, the Square de la Republique, two views taken from the Camp des Oliviers and the Route de Mansourah, and the Palais de la Justice. The two postcards of Philippeville both contain images of the Place de la Marine.
        Collection Ideale P.S.; Combier, Mâcon L.L. (Lévy & Fils); Phot. Neurdein et Cie.; Algeria, Description and travel; Colonial architecture; Gorges; Panoramic views; Street scenes
    - Subsubseries 8. Djemila
      - Djemilan.d. (1900-1950), 3 postcards (Box 1, Folder 11)
        Contains 3 postcards of the Roman ruins at Djemila. Includes images of "Le Grand Temple" and "Arc du Grand Cardo."
        CAP; Lévy et Neurdein Réunis; Algeria, Description and travel; Archaeological sites
    - Subsubseries 9. H
      - Hammam-Meskoutine, Hammam-R'hiran.d. (1900-1950), 2 postcards (Box 1, Folder 12)
        Contains 1 postcard of the Grand Pavillon de l'Etablissement at Hammam-Meskoutine. 1 postcard of the forest at Hammam-R'hira.
        J. Geiser, Alger; C. Nataf; Algeria, Description and travel; Colonial buildings
    - Subsubseries 10. Kabyila
      - Kabylian.d. (1900-1950), 3 postcards (Box 1, Folder 13)
        Contains 3 postcards with images from the Kabylia region. Includes: Le Col de Tirourda; Yakouren; Tizi-Ouzou.
        Collection Ideale, P.S.; J. Geiser, Alger; Algeria, Description and travel; Panoramic views; Street scenes
    - Subsubseries 11. El Kantara
      - El Kantaran.d. (1900-1950), 4 postcards (Box 1, Folder 14)
        Contains 4 postcards from El Kantara. Includes images of the oasis, of the railroad station, of the Gorges d'El-Kantara, and of the Pont du Diable.
        Collection D. & M.; ND Phot; Photo-Albert, Alger; Soeurs Miissionaires de N.-D. d'Afrique, Alger; Algeria, Description and travel; Gorges; Oases; Railroad stations
    - Subsubseries 12. Laghout
      - Laghouatn.d. (1900-1950), 19 postcards (Box 1, Folder 15)
        Contains images of Laghouat. Includes one series of 14 postcards from Seddik, Musée de l'Oasis, Laghouat. These contain the following images: General views, the church, the Hotel Transatlantique, Porte de la Seguia, Place du Chameau and Public gardens, Schetett street, the mosque, the Marabout of Sidi Abd-el-Kader, Quartier des Ouled-Nails, Avenue Marguerite, the Hospital. Includes 3 postcards from the Coll. Hotel Saharien, Aracil, Laghouat. These contain images of The Place du Barail, le Lavoir des Negresses, Grand Hotel Saharien. Two other images: the Mosque and the Marabout des Ouled-Aissa ben Ali.
        Combier, Mâcon; Collection Ideale P.S.; Seddik, Musée de l'Oasis, Laghouat; Algeria, Description and travel; Architecture, colonial; Markets; Mosques; Panoramic views; Religious buildings; Street scenes
    - Subsubseries 13. M
      - Maison-Carree, Meknes, Mers-el-Kebir, Moliere, M'silan.d. (1900-1950), 6 postcards (Box 1, Folder 16)
        Contains postcards from diverse towns. The images are as follows: Maison Carree: Market, Meknes: ruins of Volubilis, Mers-el-Keber: view of the fort, panoramic view, Moliere: Mosque, M'sila: sunrise over oasis
        Agenda P.L.M.; J. Barreau et Cie.; N. Boumendil & fils; E.P.A. (Editions Photo-Afriaines), Algiers; J. Geiser, Alger; ND Phot.; Algeria, Description and travel; Archaeological sites; Markets; Mosques; Panoramic views
    - Subsubseries 14. Oran
      - Orann.d. (1900-1915), 9 postcards (Box 1, Folder 17)
        Contains images of the city of Oran, including a view of the Fort Saint-Philippe, Promenade de l'Etang, the Theater, Route des Planteurs, the port, Grand Hotel d'Oran, Place Kleber and the Prefecture, a scene entitled "Fantasia au village negre."
        Aqua Photo, Paris; Edition Henri Chazaud, Oran; Collection Ideale P.S.; Grand Hotel d'Oran; ND Phot.; Algeria, Description and travel; Colonial architecture; Harbors; Panoramic views; Street scenes
    - Subsubseries 15. Palestro
      - Palestro1905, 4 postcards (Box 1, Folder 18)
        Contains four postcards from the same series. Three show the Gorges de Palestro, the fourth shows a hut in the Arab market with its owner.
        Collection Ideale, P.S.; Algeria, Description and travel; Gorges; Housing
    - Subsubseries 16. Sahara
      - Ghardaia, El-Golea, In-Guettara, Figuign.d. (1900-1950), 8 postcards (Box 1, Folder 19)
        Contains postcards from various towns in the Saharan Desert, as follows: Ghardaia: Caravan, market, "Fantasia sur la Grande Place, El Golea: panoramic view, Sahara algerien: African women making bread, In-Guettara: gorges, Figuig: Village d'El Mais, road scene
        Jouve, A., photographer; Bougault, Cl., photographer; Agenda P.L.M.; Edit. Abd'el'Kader, Ghardaia; ND Phot.; B. Sirven; Algeria, Description and travel; Caravans; Desert; Gorges; Market; Oases
    - Subsubseries 17. Setif
      - Setifn.d. (1900-1950), 4 postcards (Box 1, Folder 20)
        These four postcards contain the following images: Hotel de Ville and Portes d'Alger, Marche Arabe, Post Office, Mosque
        C,A,P.; Collection Ideale, P.S.; Algeria, Description and travel; Architecture, Colonial; Markets; Mosques; Street scenes
    - Subsubseries 18. S
      - Sidi-Bel-Abbes, Sidi-Bou-Medine, Sidi-Okban.d. (1900-1960), 6 postcards (Box 1, Folder 21)
        Contains the following images: Sidi-Bel-Abbes: Public Gardens, Marabout, Sidi-Bou-Medine: panoramic view, Sidi-Okba: La Grande Place, the Market
        CAP; N.D. Phot.; R. Prouho; A. Bougault; Algeria, Description and travel; Markets; Panoramic views; Religious buildings; Street scenes
    - Subsubseries 19. Tebessa
      - Tebessa1907, 3 postcards (Box 1, Folder 22)
        Postcards of Tebessa, including a view taken from the Route de Zouira and the ramparts of the Byzantine citadel.
        ND Phot.; Algeria, Description and travel; Forts and fortifications; Panoramic views
    - Subsubseries 20. Timgad
      - Timgadn.d. (1900-1945), 29 postcards (Box 1, Folder 23)
        Timgad contains a major site of Roman ruins. The CAP series of 22 postcards contains the following images, (some duplicates): Arc of Trajan; Amphitheater, Columns for Pronaos du Capitole; Byzantine baptistery; Market; Gardens; Forum; Boutiques in the Sirtius market; Temple of Genie; Roman baths and mosaics. The ND Phot series of 6 postcards contains views of: Gardens; columns; the theater, the baths; mosaics. Collection Ideale PS: Hemicycle of Macellum.
        CAP; Collection Ideale, P.S.; ND Phot; Algeria, Description and travel; Archaeological sites
    - Subsubseries 21. Tlemcen
      - Tlemcenn.d. (1900-1950), 5 (Box 1, Folder 24)
        Contains the following images: Ruins of the Fortress of Toubiana; Tower of Mansourah; Oued-Mefrouch-el-Ourit Waterfall; Mosque of Sidi-Bou-Medine; Ruins of Sidi-Yacoub.
        ND Phot.; LL; Photo Sandoz; Algeria, Description and travel; Archaeological sites; Gorges; Mosques; Religious buildings
    - Subsubseries 22. Touggourt
      - Touggourtn.d. (c 1930), 2 postcards (Box 1, Folder 25)
        One image of Ouled-Nail women sitting before their tents; one image of the Grande Place at Touggourt.
        Prouho, Cl., photographer; Agenda P.L.M.; SPGA; Algeria, Description and travel; Muslim women; Street scenes
    - Subsubseries 23. Scenes and types
      - Scenes and types from Algerian.d. (1900-1950), 15 postcards (Box 1, Folder 26)
        Various postcards showing Algerian individuals or groups, either presented as an archetype, or as an example of a traditional occupation. Also includes some street scenes and desert scenes, and examples of indigenous housing. Images include: Mauresques and Maures, Mozabite man, women washing, the firewood market, the Constantine Phosphate company, a caravan, Kabyle and Arab huts, and a historical painting of fighting at Sig.
        CAP; Collection Ideale, P.S.; Collection Z.F., Alger; Imprimeries Reunies, Nancy; Editions Marius Maure, Biskra; LL ND Phot.; Algeria, Description and travel; Caravans; Desert; Fuelwood; Housing; Indigenous peoples; Laundry; Street scenes; Women
- Series 2. Arabian
  - Aden, Persia (Iran), Saudi Arabian.d. (1900-1950), 8 postcards (Box 1, Folder 27)
    This folder contains 6 postcards from Aden. These have images of city, the water tanks, the fruit market, Steamer Point, and a caravan. One postcard from Saudi Arabia pictures a mosque. One picture from Persia shows a grouping of people around a patriarch for a festival.
    M. Howard, photographer; Egyptian Cigarettes Factory; Hotel de l'Europe, Aden; M.S. Lehem & Co.; Seyed Abdor Rahime Tachani, Teheran, Persia; Aden, Description and Travel; Harbors; Markets; Mosques; Panoramic views; People
- Series 3. British East Africa
  - Kenya, Tanganyika, Uganda, Zanzibarn.d. (1900-1960), 17 postcards (Box 1, Folder 28)
    The 9 postcards of British East Africa include the following images: a shepherd, Arab architecture, a view from Nairobi Hill, a native village, and hunting and animal scenes. The 4 postcards from Zanzibar includean image of the Beit-el-Ajaib (the house of wonders), the Ladies' Club and Jubilee Garden, the Country Palace of the Sultan, and Dhow Harbour. One postcard from the Freres Blancs, Uganda, of Missionaries hunting. One postcard of Mt. Kibo, Tanganyika.
    A.R.P. de Lord, Zanzibar; K.T. Rawal, Zanzibar; Moloo Brothers & Co. British East Africa; Propagation de la Foi; H.J. Schlieben; V. Neubert, Prague; Standard P. & P. Works, British East Africa; Architecture, colonial; Big game hunting; Game and game birds; Harbors; Indigenous peoples; Panoramic views; Porters; Shepherds
- Series 4. British West Africa
  - Ghana, Nigerian.d. (1929-1962), 4 postcards (Box 1, Folder 29)
    2 postcards from Nigeria: a water seller, cliffs on coast outside of Lagos 2 postcards from Ghana: the General Post Office and Kano City
    Jackie Phillips Photos, Lagos; E.A. Sweetman & Son, Ltd.; Cliffs; Ghana, Description and travel; Nigeria, Description and travel; Post offices; Street scenes; Water carriers
- Series 5. Belgian Congo
  - Belgian Congo1900-1960, 37 postcards (Box 1, Folder 30)
    This folder contains 37 postcards with images of the Belgian Congo (1908-1960). Included are postcards from the towns of: Boko, Boma, Bukama, Elisabethville, Kafubu, Chutes Ki-Oubo, Matadi, Kivu, Remondville, Stanleyville. Postcards depicting fishing in the Upper Congo, on the Tanganiki, a marketplace, elephants in the river at Also Postcards of people working: "un corps de balais" (women sweeping, a pun on corps de ballet), a rice plantation, hair-stylists. Postcard of a tribal chief and his many wives. Postcards showing colonial power: hunting, military posts, colonial forces of order. Postcards showing missionary work. 3 postcards printed by Belgian marine interests.
    L'Olivier, Allard; van Parys, G., Photographer; Editions d'Art E. Mertens, Brussels; Edition R. Begue, Paris; Cie. Francaise du Haut-Congo; Compagnie Maritime du Congo, Anvers; Edit. Librairie J. Decoster, Elisabethville; Delhaize Freres & Cie, "Le Lion"; Desaix, Brussels; E. Desclee; Ed. Jesuites Missionnaires, Lyon; Missions de Scheut; Nels, Brussels; Th. Luyckx, Wavre; Ern. Thill, Brussels; Edition V.M.W. et M.B.; C. Van Cortenbergh Fils, Brussels; Architecture, colonial; Belgian Congo; Boats; Bridges; Colonial power; Elephants; Fishing; Forts and fortifications; Harbors; Hospitals; Indigenous peoples; Markets; Panaramic views; Post office; Waterfalls; Women
- Series 6. Congo (Brazzaville)
  - Africa, French speaking equatorial including Lower and Middle Congo, Chad, Cameroonn.d. (1900-1960), 25 postcards (Box 1, Folder 31)
    This folder contains postcards from the area formerly known as Congo (Brazzaville) or French Equatorial Africa. 17 postcards of Brazzaville: Institut Pasteur, le Relais Hotel, Jardins de la Residence, Catholic Mission and Cathedral, Catholic procession, View from Route de la Corniche (Belgian Congo), Djoue riverbank, Congo riverbank, bridge over M'Foa, fishermen and flottila, Woman from Brazzaville. 1 postcard of the railroad of Matadi, Compagnie Francaise du Haut-Congo. 1 postcard of caravan with missionaries 1 postcard of small tugboat on river 1 postcard of Tirailleurs senegalais 1 postcard of a monument to Colonel de Roux, Bangui 1 postcard of Danse goran, Chad 2 postcards, indigenous art, French Cameroon
    M. Audrey, Marseille; Braban Cliche Vialle, Brazzaville; Collection J.F.; Collections A. Courboin; Editions artistiques, Pierre Barreau, Bordeaux; Edit. M. Brochard, Nantes; "La Librairie Congolaise", Brazzaville; Levy et Neurdein Reunis, Paris; Missions des Pretres du Sacre-Coeur de St Quentin; Photo M. Balard, Bangui; Africa, French speaking equatorial; Colonial power; Congo (Brazzaville); Fishing; Missionaries; Panoramic views; Rivers; Street scenes
- Series 7. Cote d'Ivoire
  - Cote d'Ivoiren.d., 4 postcards (Box 1, Folder 32)
    4 postcards from Cote d'Ivoire: Embarcation of mahogany in Grand Lahou Pushing the tiller, Grand Lahou Village devastated by Samory (the Black Napoleon) in 1898, A river in the forest
    Collection M.M.A.C.B.; Colonial commerce; Cote d'Ivoire; Mahogany trees; Rivers; Villages
- Series 8. Dahomey
  - Dahomeyn.d., 8 postcards (Box 1, Folder 33)
    8 postcards from Dahomey. Cotonou: Monument for soldiers, Market, Grand Popo, Ouida: village, Porto-Novo: bridge, river, Fishing village, Prince's wedding
    Editions E.R.; Cl. Andre; Bridges; Dahomey; Markets; Monuments; Villages; Weddings